Jasir KT

Software Developer

(+91) 9645 11 93 93 meetjasir@gmail.com https://jasir.dev Bangalore, India

OVERVIEW

Certified full stack developer with 4 years of experience. Specialized in backend development. Worked on **Java/J2EE** for 2 years and **React.js+Node.js** for 2 years. Skilled in **MySQL** database design and optimization. Worked on **Scaling, Rest APIs, Redis, Linux Servers and AWS**.

SKILLS

Languages: Java, React.js, Node.js, HTML, CSS

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL

UI Frameworks: Material UI for React, Java FX

Unit Testing: JUnit

SCM: Git

Build Tools: Gradle

Logging Framework: log4j

ORM: Sequelize

EXPERIENCE

Zoho, Remote - Member Technical Staff

NOV 2020 - PRESENT

Working on payment integration in Zoho.

Causematch, Bangalore - Developer

NOV 2018 - NOV 2020

- Worked on scaling the platform.
- Worked on integrating various payment gateways.
- Worked on integrating voucher payment services.
- Worked with the team to redesign the entire platform from scratch for moving to a reliable stack

Technologies

React.js, Node.js, AWS, Redis, Sequelize ORM.

Zoho, Chennai - Member Technical Staff

JUN 2016 - JULY 2018

• Enhanced the framework for Zoho Finance Suite of applications

Mentored several junior engineers and partially managed teams

Hands on experience in working with cloud computing architecture

Developed a tool for live performance monitoring of MySQL database

Worked on a testing automation tool

Worked on integrating UPI and BharatQR payments

Technologies

Core Java, MySQL, Redis, Docker.

Projects

Zoho Finance Framework: This is the framework on top of which around 7+ Zoho Finance Applications run. The main functionalities included providing a secure database interface, enabling easy database migrations, providing a framework for running asynchronous jobs and enforcing strict security protocols.

Zoho Books: Zoho Books is an online accounting software to manage accounting, inventory and to file GST returns with ease.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Kolikkal Info - Android Application

This is an ongoing project that aims at bringing together every information about Kolikkal village under one application.

Technologies Used: Java (Android), SQLite, Firestore, Node.js, Firebase cloud messaging.

Kamiz Accounting - Java based Desktop Application

Accounting Software developed for Kamiz textiles. 2 other businesses are also using it currently.

Technologies Used: Java, Swing, H2 database.

Spider Calicut - Java based Desktop Application

This was a district directory for Calicut district, Kerala. It included quick search, auto updates among other features. The software was launched by M.K Ragahavan, the MP of Kozhikode Loksabha constituency.

Technologies Used: Java, Swing, Java DB.

FAID - Web application

This was a project aimed at farmers and krishi bhavans. The primary goal was to eliminate all paperwork from krishi bhavans, and to have a unified platform for farmers.

Technologies Used: MySQL, PHP, Bootstrap.

EDUCATION

College of Engineering Adoor - B.Tech (Computer Science)

JUNE 2012 -

AISSCE Std. 12th - Maths, Computer Science

JULY 2009 - MAR 2011

AISSCE Std. 10th

MAR 2009

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Awarded 'GALACTIC PROBLEM SOLVER' at International Space Apps Challenge conducted by NASA.
- Third place in national level coding competition 'POWERHOUSE CODING' conducted at Rajagiri School of Engineering and Technology
- First price in 'Blind-C' coding competition conducted by TRACE at College of Engineering Adoor
- Participated in **Accubotz Sixth Sense Robotics** program

PERSONAL INTERESTS

- Motorcycle riding
- Blogging
- Reading
- Gardening
- Skygazing

LANGUAGES

- English (Proficient)
- Malayalam (Native)
- Hindi (Beginner)
- Arabic (Read&Write, Beginner)
- Tamil (Speak, Beginner)